Dawn Narikkattu Mathews

Web Developer

CONTACT INFORMATION & LANGUAGES

7-7336, Sherbrooke Street West, Montreal, QC H4B 1R7 438.220.7860

mathewsdawn3@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/dawn-mathews-71156117a

Portfolio Website: https://dawnnm.github.io/

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Motivated Web Developer with experience creating custom websites and android apps through HTML, CSS, Javascript, React and PHP. I have undertaken intensive studies in Programming and Web Technologies. I have experience designing, developing and deploying web and mobile applications. I am an effective communicator with good organizational skills. I also like solving problems and enjoy working in a team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, JAVA, SQL, Python, Ajax, C / C++, XML

Frameworks : Codelgniter, MVC, Bootstrap, Jquery, ECMAScript 6

Issue Tracking : JIRA, Trello

OS : Windows, Linux, Mac

Methodologies : Agile, Scrum Methodology, Object oriented design, Design Patterns, SDLC, TDD

: UML, Use Case, Class, Activity & Sequence Diagram, Storyboarding Modelling **Tools** : Eclipse SDK, Android studio, Visual Studio, Adobe Creative Suite

Web Technologies: React, NodeJS, SOAP & REST APIS

CMS Tools : Wordpress, Elementor **Database** : MySQL, MongoDB

Version Control : Junit testing, Bitbucket, Jenkins, Git **Web Server** : XAMP, LAMP, Apache Tomcat

EDUCATION

Programming and Web Technologies, Attestation of College Studies

Institute Superieur d'Informatique - Montreal

Computer Science and Engineering, Bachelor of Technology

Christ University Faculty Of Engineering - Bangalore

INTERNSHIP

Anti-Theft Bike Tracking Solution

May 2016 - June 2016

2019 - 2021

2013 - 2017

Tech Mahindra, Bangalore

- Anti-Theft Bike Tracking Solution is an Arduino based IOT project to improve the security of a bike by continuously tracking the location of vehicle. In this project, we did the following tasks.
- Develop a prototype device using Arduino and GPS Sensors to track the location of a bike.
- Notify owner if someone moves the vehicle without the knowledge of the owner with a text message or email.

- Program the Arduino to fetch and analyse the sensor data from GPS module and notify the user using GSM and ESP8266 wifi module.
- Programming languages, hardware and software used: C++, Arduino, ESP8266, GSM, GPS, Sensors

PROJECTS

StyleStamp - Ecommerce Fashion Store

- StyleStamp is an ecommerce android application to sell fashion accessories with a website for admin user to manage products, categories, orders and user information.
- Created functions in settings and order model to retrieve data from database, added controller for loading and passing data to view orders page and worked on the functionality for admin to view or delete orders on website.
- Also created rest APIs to filter products, retrieve customer profile, cancel order, create order, get orders by status, verify login and retrieve settings.
- Technologies used were Codeigniter, PHP, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, Android Studio, Java, XAMP, MySQL
- Github Link: https://github.com/dawnNM/StyleStamp
- Project Link: http://stylestamp.c1.biz/ (Username: admin@gmail.com, Password: Abc@1234)
- Portfolio Page Link: https://dawnnm.github.io/dawnmathews/stylestamp.html

CardsMatch – A Memory Game using cards

- CardsMatch is a Memory Card Game. In this game, the player has to flip 2 cards each time and memorize its position. In order to win, all the identical cards have to be matched.
- Designed the layout as a horizontal and vertical array of tiles and when the user clicks on a tile, it flips.
- If the two cards are the same number and of same color, it is matched. User wins the game by matching all the cards. The goal is to do it in the least number of moves. Added 4 different difficulty levels with more cards: 4 x 4, 4 x 6, 4 x 8, 6 x 6.
- Languages used for this project are HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Github Link: https://github.com/dawnNM/CardsMemoryGame
- Project Link: https://mathewsd3.github.io/CardsMemoryGame/
- Portfolio Page Link: https://dawnnm.github.io/dawnmathews/cardsmatch.html

ISIDrone - Ecommerce Website for Selling Drones

- ISIDrone is an ecommerce website where customers can buy drones by adding items to cart. Admin user can add, modify and delete items sold in the website. The admin user can also manage categories, orders and customers through the website.
- In this project I worked on the functionality for the admin user to either add, delete, view and modify Products and Orders.
- Languages and technologies used in this project are JAVA, JSP, Servlet, MAVEN, MySQL, JavaScript, GIT, BitBucket, Putty, WinSCP and Jenkins
- Github Link : https://github.com/dawnNM/ISIDrone
- Bitbucket Link: https://bitbucket.org/isiteachers/devint-en-yellow/src/master/
- Portfolio Page Link: https://dawnnm.github.io/dawnmathews/isidrone.html

Meenachil Restaurant - Website for an Indian Restaurant

- Meenachil Restaurant is an responsive, dynamic and mobile friendly website for an Indian Restaurant
- This restaurant website has six main pages which are home, menu, gallery, reservation, about and contact.
- Technologies used were HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Jquery and JavaScript
- Github Link: https://github.com/dawnNM/MeenachilRestaurant
- Project Link: http://meenachilrestaurant.c1.biz/
- Portfolio Page Link: https://dawnnm.github.io/dawnmathews/meenachilrestaurant.html

Music Box – A Discogs App For Searching Songs

- Music Box is a web application for searching music tracks on discogs, which is a online music database where we can buy and sell tracks.
- This web app searches through the discogs database of information about audio recordings, including commercial releases, promotional releases, and off-label releases and utilizes the **discogs api** to query and fetch data in JSON format.
- Technologies used for this project are React, MySQL and NodeJS
- Github Link : https://github.com/dawnNM/MusicBox
- Portfolio Page Link : https://dawnnm.github.io/dawnmathews/musicbox.html

Quiz App - A GK Quiz App for Android

- Developed an android general knowledge quiz application with multiple levels of difficulty
- User is given 30 seconds for answers each guiz questions and the result is displayed on finishing the guiz
- Software used was android studio and the language used was JAVA.
- Github Link : https://github.com/dawnNM/QuizApp
- Portfolio Page Link: https://dawnnm.github.io/dawnmathews/quizapp.html

Travel Time - A Travel Agency website

- TravelTime is a website for a travel agency. Users can view the different locations that they would like to visit through the website.
- Displays beautiful images of various places people could visit. There is option for customers to view various travel plans and contact the company.
- Languages used for this project are HTML, CSS, BootStrap and JavaScript
- Github Link: https://github.com/mathewsd3/ExploreTheWorld
- Project Link: https://mathewsd3.github.io/ExploreTheWorld/
- Portfolio Page Link: https://dawnnm.github.io/dawnmathews/traveltime.html

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Cashier April 2020 - Present

Fruiterie Green Canadian, Montreal

- Greet customers warmly and promote customer loyalty
- Process transactions very precisely
- Keep all checkout work stations clean, tidy, and uncluttered
- Produce and balance the cash report at the end of each shift
- Taking orders in person and over the phone
- Stock supply making a list of missing articles for purchasing

Kitchen Helper February 2019 – March 2020

Le Caractere Chinois, Montreal

- Prepare wontons and dumplings for the Chef
- Cut vegetables for making egg roll
- Cut and marinate meat for Chef to make General Tao
- Do other kitchen work like cleaning

REFERENCES

References available upon request